Alexandr Romanov

Current Location: Almaty, Kazakhstan (Open to relocation)

Email: downitch@proton.me Phone: +77711462116

Website: https://downtich.github.io

Languages: Russian, English (C1), German (C1)

Summary

Software Developer

With over 10 years of programming experience in both nonprofit & commercial startups dealing with high-load & high-demand tasks, Alexandr is keen on pivoting their career towards penetration testing and cyber security.

Penetration Tester

After a great journey as a self-taught software developer, Alexandr decided to pivot their career towards cyber security and penetration testing. Attending University and becoming a certified bug bounty hunter are Alexandr's first milestones in this field.

Privacy Enthusiast

Alexandr's passion is world where people have total privacy. In an attempt to pursue this goal, Alexandr joined several startups and delivered solutions that enhanced privacy of the users by utilizing both Tor and P2P networking.

Blockchain Expert

After joining the crypto scene back in 2016, Alexandr pursued their passion in both spreading and creating educational content related to blockchain technologies. Alexandr has experience in embedding blockchain solutions into emerging and running businesses. Special speaker at multiple community and commercial based blockchain conferences.

Experience

Bug Bounty Hunter

HACKERONE/INTIGRITI

Jul 2022 - Present

Penetration testing of both public and private bug bounty programs. Working with white-, gray-, black-box scenarios. Web-app, mobile-app, network penetration testing. Report writing, Attack chaining, Vector- & Attack-pivoting. Ruby/Bash/Python complex scan&exploit / automation scripts development. Static-code analysis in JavaScript & PHP.

Lead Software Developer

APPHOLD LLC

May 2019 - Mar 2022 (2 years 11 months)

Combining Golang with iOS and Android mainstream development technologies. Creating a P2P messaging application based on Tor and Ethereum blockchain. Fully anonymized, decentralized and transparent communication with no single point of failure.

Fullstack Software Developer

Atom Industries

Apr 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 3 months)

Creating a Golang implementation of a mobile application that would ease access to onion overlay network.

Education

University of Wollongong (UOW), Australia

Bachelor of Computer Science - BSc, Cyber Security Jul 2021 - Jul 2024 (Undergraduate Degree acquired)

KIT, Germany

Bachelor of Computer Science - BSc, Informatics Jul 2014 - Jul 2015 (Unfinished)

Licenses & Certifications

Hack The Box Certified Bug Bounty Hunter (HTB CBBH) - Hack The Box

Verification code: HTBCERT-CB49883565

Obtained: 09/13/2023